Contact

zukangy1@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/zukang-yang (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Python

Statistics

R/R studio

Languages

Mandarin Chinese (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Survival Analysis in R

Practical Deep Learning with Pytorch

Zukang Y.

B.S. Grad in Mathematics & Statistics| Looking for Data Scientist roles in California| Python | R | MySQL | Pytorch | TensorFlow | Time Series

Irvine, California

Summary

I have a Bachelor's degree in Mathematics with a specialization in Data Science, and a minor in Statistics. I enjoy wrangling data and discovering insights and patterns from the data and turning them into profitable business products.

I have fundamental skills in Data and Programming

- * Programming languages: Python 3, R, Matlab, and SQL.
- * Databases: MySQL, and PostgreSQL
- * Machine Learning Algorithms: Regression, Classification, Clustering, Dimensionality Reduction, KNN,

Deep Learning, and Transfer Learning.

* Tools: Git, Github, Scrapy, and Tableau

Aside from data science, I also enjoy reading, cooking, racquetball, and investment.

Feel free to contact me regarding any possible job opportunities at zukangy1@gmail.com

Experience

Eonum, Inc.

Data Scientist

December 2019 - Present (4 months)

Irvine, California

- Building a long-short equity trading algorithm with zipline library in Python for hedge fund client to trade US stocks for 6 months, using metrics such as return and max drawdown for evaluation
- Leading a team of three data scientists following the Agile Kanban methodology; arranging regular meetings for team members and presentations to the founders

• Identifying available and suitable data from different sources such as Quandl and IEX Cloud for backtesting the algorithm; creating data pipelines in Python to store and move the data between MySQL database and Python

Enhance IT
Data Scientist
August 2019 - January 2020 (6 months)
Greater Atlanta Area

- Built a dynamic machine learning model to appraise home values for single-family homes in Pima County, Arizona, replacing the need to hire professional appraisers and resulting in an estimated profit of \$200k
- Utilized web scraping tools like Scrapy to appropriately retrieve about 110k housing data from various web servers for the model
- Cleaned data including missing value imputation, outlier detection, rescaling, and one-hot encoding, ensuring the data is in the correct format for the machine learning model
- Engineered features to generate relevant explanatory variables; tested the significance of these features with permutation feature importance technique
- Compared various machine learning models such as linear models, tree-based models and ensembled models using Python; performed hyperparameter tuning with grid search, and selected the final model by leveraging the trade-off between interpretability and predictive power
- Documented the model and provided guidance to the software engineering team to productionize the model for the client and communicated the results to clients and other members of the team

UCI Fresh Basic Needs Hub Student Coordinator July 2018 - June 2019 (1 year) Irvine, CA

Greeting students and community members and provide necessary information regarding

the food pantry and how to access the service or support the service through donations.

Implementing food pantry policies and procedures.

Coordinating all organization for the pantry & storage areas.

Assisting with inventory control and ensure proper procedures are followed.

Assisting with procurement processes to acquire resources (OC Food Bank, Grocery
Rescue)

Providing daily assistance to food pantry volunteers.

Education

UC Irvine
Bachelor's degree, Mathematics

UC Irvine
Minor, Statistics